aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Vicious prisoners escaped from the Space Prison of Sargasso, and have begun their planetary galley.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들이 혹성 사냥을 개시했다
In order to protect the peace of Earth, Brave Seijin of the Space Police granted these brave heroes powers.
지구의 평화를 지키기 위해 우주 경찰 기구의 브레이브 성인이 힘을 내려준 용자(勇者)들
Their name is Dagwon.
그 이름은 다그온
Now, a new comrade has joined them.
그들에게 지금 새로운 동료가 가담했다
White Wings Dancing in the Wind
바람에 흩날리는 하얀 날개
Space Demon Demos
Appears
우주의 악마 데모스 성인
등장
I'll come back soon from stationary store.
그럼 잠깐 문구점에 다녀올게요
Thank you for everything, Ms. Anna.
항상 미안해요, 안나 선생님
No problem.
천만에요
I must get going.
다녀오겠습니다
I don't know about this, but...
그럼 한번 먹어볼까?
Hot!
매, 매워~!
Who the heck eats this?!
이, 이딴걸 누가 먹냐?!
It's hot?
그렇습니까?
I always thought spicy curry bread here was always the best.
여기서 파는 엄청 매운 카레빵, 최고라고 생각했는데요
My neck is burning...
목이, 목이 타들어가는 것 같다
I was like that too.
처음엔 나도 그랬다
But, I'm alright now!
하지만, 지금은 전혀 끄떡없지!
Hot! Tasty!
맵다! 맛있다!
I finally found you, Anna.
드디어 찾았구나, 안나
It's been some time.
이거 오랜만이군!
You're running away?
도망칠 셈이냐?
I will not let you run away, Anna!
놓치지 않는다, 안나! 이자식!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Fire En!
파이어 엔!
I am burning up after eating something hot!
매운걸 먹었더니 왠지 달아오르는걸!
So you guys are Dagwon.
네놈들이 다그온이냐?
Do not interfere!
방해하지 마라!
No!
안돼!
Hurry! Please hurry and run away!
어서! 어서 도망치세요!
Damn you!
이자식!
-Stop it, brother!
-Brother?!
-그만둬요, 오빠!
-오빠?!
Someone help me!
누가.. 누가 좀 도와줘요!
No!
큰일이다!
Die! Dagwon!
뒈져라! 다그온!
No! Kyo!
안돼! 카아 쨩!
The baby is safe.
아기는 무사합니다
Thank you so much.
정말 감사합니다
En!
엔!
Die!
뒈져라!
Shoulder Burn!
숄더 번!
Blizzard Hurricane!
블리자드 허리케인!
Drill Vulcan!
드릴 발칸!
You shall regret concerning yourselves with my things!
내 일에 관여한 걸 후회하지 마라!
I will make you pay severely.
이 빚은 톡톡히 갚아주마
Anna!
안나여!
I will never forgive you!
난 널 용서하지 않는다!
Especially after you betrayed me!
배신자인 널 말이다!
You will never be able to run away from me!
내게서 도망칠 수 있을 거라 생각 마라!
What the heck is going on here?
이게 대체 어떻게 된 거죠?
Do you have something to tell us?
설명해 주시겠습니까?
Yes.
네...
What were you doing, Ms. Anna?
뭐하고 있었어요, 안나 선생님?
We were waiting for a while.
저희들, 쭉~ 기다렸다구요
Sorry. Everyone, I'm sorry.
미안해, 얘들아 미안해
Even if it's already time to go back home,
벌써 돌아갈 시간이 한참 지났는데도
they aren't going back, saying that they must say bye to Ms. Anna.
모두들 안나 선생님에게 작별 인사 하겠다며 돌아가질 않네요
Sorry, Ms. Ryoko.
죄송합니다, 료코 선생님
It's already late. Let's go back, children.
자, 벌써 늦은 시간이구나 돌아가자, 얘들아
Yes!
네~~~~
Ms. Anna is a sister of that huge monster?
안나 선생님이 그 괴물과 형제라니...
A twin?
그것도 쌍둥이라니 말야
Yeah, this is totally unbelievable.
그래, 정말 믿기질 않는다구
Right. Demos is my brother, certainly.
그래요, 틀림없이 데모스는 제 오빠입니다
My brother destoyed lots of planets continuously, since he has an evil nature.
오빠는 본성이 사악해서 수많은 별들을 끊임없이 파괴했습니다
I couldn't stand staying quiet.
그런 오빠를 전 가만히 보고 있을 수 없었어요
So that's why you reported him to Brave Seijin.
그래서 브레이브 성인에게 신고한 거군요
Anna!
안나!
You reported me! You traitor!
날 경찰에 찔렀구나! 배신했구나!
That was the only thing that I could do.
그 외엔 방법이 없었습니다
But, why are they so different?
하지만, 어째서 남매가 저리도 다른거지?
This might explain: every person has a good and evil nature inside.
그건 이렇게 볼 수 있습니다 사람의 마음에는 선(善)과 악(惡)이 있죠?
Normally, they are born with those two together.
보통은 그걸 함께 가지고 태어납니다
But Demos and Ms. Anna are a special kind of twins.
하지만 데모스와 안나 선생님의 경우는 특수한 쌍둥이로
They have each one of them.
그걸 따로 가진 채 태어난 겁니다
So you're saying that Demos only has the evil nature...
그 말은, 악의 마음만을 데모스가 가지고
...and Ms. Anna only has the good nature.
선의 마음만을 안나 선생님이 가지고 태어났단 말이군
It must've been painful.
괴로웠겠지
To place her brother under arrest...
친 오빠를 신고하다니...
I think I might understand her desire to abandon her home.
고향을 버리고 싶어하는 마음, 왠지 알 것 같군
She was living in peace on the Earth in secret...
모처럼 이 지구에서 남몰래 살아가고 있었는데
Sargasso is a den of demons now.
지금의 사르갓소는 악마의 소굴입니다
And Demos came to Earth to seek revenge on Ms. Anna.
그리고 데모스는 안나 선생님에게 복수하기 위해 지구에 온 거군요
He's messing around!
정말 놀고 있구만!
Such things deserved to be resented in return!
그딴 녀석, 남매도 아니야!
Everyone! Calm down! Stay in your seats!
얘들아, 침착해! 침착하렴!
What?! He captured a school bus?
뭐야?! 스쿨 버스가 붙잡혔다고?!
Yeah! It's been captured by a giant hand and it's flying high!
그래! 거대한 손에 붙잡혀서 상당히 높은 곳까지 올라가 있어!
No good.
안돼!
The target is too close to the bus!
녀석이 버스에 너무 붙어있어!
Now, Dagwon, give me Anna!
자, 다그온이여! 안나를 내게 넘겨라!
Or I'll take the children's lives first!
안 그러면 꼬마들 목숨은 없는 줄 알아라!
You bastard! That's dirty!
이자식, 비열한 수를 쓰다니!
Wait!
기다려요!
-Where are you going?
-Let me go! I will go!
-뭘 어쩔 셈이예요?!
-이거 놔요! 제가 가겠어요!
Calm down! We'll do anything!
침착해요! 우리가 어떻게든 해 볼게요!
This is my responsibility!
이건 제 책임이예요!
If whatever happens to them, it's my...
그 아이들에게 무슨 일이 생기면 모두 제...
N- no...
그, 그런...
I don't care about what happens to me!
전 어떻게 되든 상관없어요!
So, please save the children...
그러니, 그러니 아이들을...
Ms. Anna...
아, 안나 선생님
Now, brother...
자, 오빠
Let the children and Ms. Ryoko go.
아이들과 료코 선생님을 돌려보내 주세요
You and I are tied by the bond of fate.
나와 넌 운명의 연(絆)으로 이어져 있다
We cannot separate.
절대 서로 떨어질 수 없는 거다
Now, come to me.
자, 이리로 와라
Much closer.
좀 더 가까이 와라
It's him.
녀석이 녀석인 만큼
He won't let go of the children that easily. We're counting on you for backup, Shin.
간단히 아이들을 넘겨줄 거라고 생각하진 않아 엄호 부탁한다, 신!
Leave it to me!
맡겨 두라구
You promised, brother. Please put down the bus.
약속했잖아요, 오빠 어서 버스를 내려줘요
No problem, if you say so.
거 좋지, 네가 그렇게까지 말한다면 말야
-That damned...
-Yoku!                 -Right!
-망할!
-요쿠!              -알았습니다!
Wh-what?!
아, 아니?!
Fire Knuckle!
파이어 너클!
Turbo Wheel Attack!
터보 호일 어택!
-Run away now while you still can!
-Yes!
-이틈에 도망쳐요!
-네!
Do not interfere!
방해하지 마라!
You idiot!
멍청한 자식!
You call yourself a brother when you don't understand how your sister feels?!
동생 마음도 모르면서, 네가 그러고도 오빠냐?!
Shut up!
닥쳐라!
That's as far as you go!
잠깐, 거기까지다!
Now, surrender tamely!
자, 순순히 항복하시지
That bastard! Where did he go?
이놈! 어디로 사라졌지?
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Wait! I'm going now!
기다려, 지금 간다!
Where are you going, Anna?
어딜 가려는 거냐, 안나?
I'm going to save the children!
아이들을 구하러 갈 거예요!
You're too late.
이미 늦었다
Hurry up! The magma already rose to here!
서둘러! 용암이 여기까지 올라왔다구!
-What?!
-Hey, En!
-뭐야?!
-이봐, 엔!
I hear you!
듣고 있어!
Everything will be alright.
자, 이제 괜찮아
Geki! Yoku! Escape!
게키, 요쿠! 탈출한다!
That was close.
휴~ 살았다
What happened to Ms. Anna?
안나 선생님은 어딨지?
It can't be! Did Demos take...
설마... 데모스에게?!
Feeling pain? I have a throbbing pain too.
아픈가? 나도 욱신거리고 아프다
When you get injured, I get injured too.
네가 다치면 나도 다친다
When I get inured, you get injured too.
내가 다치면 너도 다치지
I've had enough of this.
이제 정말 지긋지긋하다!
Brother...
오빠...
It is annoying whenever you do something useless.
성가시단 말이다 네가 허튼 짓을 하면 말야
Whenever something happens to your body, I am always forced to be involved.
만약 네 몸에 무슨 일이 생기면 나까지 말려들고 말아
Most of all, you reported me, your brother, to Brave Seijin,
무엇보다도 넌 오빠인 나를 브레이브 성인에게 신고했다
I cannot trust you!
믿을 수 없어!
This is Ryu. En, please respond!
여기는 류. 엔, 응답해라!
Brother!
오빠...
What are you trying to do?
무, 무슨 짓을 하려는 거예요?
I'm going to settle this fate.
운명과 결판을 지으려는 거다
That is, our fate of being special twins!
특수한 쌍둥이로 태어난 나와 너의 운명 말이다!
Brother! What is this?
오, 오빠! 뭐예요, 이건?!
A cryonics chamber.
냉동 수면 장치다
Cryonics chamber?!
냉동 수면 장치?!
You will sleep here for the eternity alive.
넌 살아있는 채로 이곳에서 영원히 잠드는 거다
Because you are my only weak point.
내 유일한 약점이니까 말야
Farewell, dear sister.
작별이다, 동생아
From now on, I'll be able to do evil deeds without any worries.
난 이걸로 안심하고 악행을 저지를 수 있지
Brother! Please don't, brother
오빠! 기다려요, 오빠!
Brother!
오빠!
-Where did you say?
-In the middle of this mountain.
-어디라고?!
-이 산의 중턱이다
Demos!
데모스!
He's heading for the city.
마을로 향하고 있어!
Follow him, Ryu!
데모스를 따라가라, 류!
I'll be right there as soon as I go rescue Ms. Anna.
난 안나 선생님을 구출 한 후에 바로 갈게
Understood!
알았어!
I'll kill everyone!
모두 때려부숴 주지!
I will make the Earth a planet of death!
이 지구를 죽음의 별로 만들어 주마!
Stop!
기다려!
I, Super Liner Dagwon, will not let you do whatever you want!
이 슈퍼 라이너 다그온이 네놈 멋대로 날뛰게 내버려두진 않는다!
Dagwon, I'll make you regret interfering with me!
다그온, 날 방해한 걸 뼈저리게 후회하도록 만들어 주마!
Teacher!
선생님!
Ms. Anna!
안나 선생님!
I see what this device does.
과연, 보안 장치라는 거냐?
But!
하지만 말이다!
Such things will not stop me!
그딴 걸로 날 막을 순 없어!
I won't be defeated!
당할 성 싶으냐?!
I won't be defeated with this!
이정도로 당할 것 같냐?!
I am perfectly fine with this!
난 이런 걸론 끄떡도 않는다구!
Do not underestimate me!
얕보지 말란 말이다!
M-Ms. Anna...
안나 선생님...
What?
뭐냐, 벌써 끝이냐?
What a disappointment!
재미없는 녀석이군!
I, Shadow Dagwon, will face you this time!
이번엔 이 섀도우 다그온이 상대해 주마!
Heh. Another small fry.
흥, 피라미가 한마리 더 늘었군
Don't be ridiculous!
웃기지 마라!
Shadow Cannon!
섀도우 캐논!
Teacher! Ms. Anna!
선생님! 안나 선생님!
What a relief!
다행이다...
The children-!
아이들은요?
It's alright. The children and Ms. Ryoko are fine.
괜찮아요, 아이들도 료코 선생님도 모두 무사해요
Thank you. Thank you so much!
감사합니다, 정말 감사합니다
Now, let's go.
자, 여기서 나갑시다
En! Take down my brother!
엔! 오빠를 해치워 주세요!
My brother is a devil. Please protect the Earth.
오빠는 악마예요 이 지구를 지켜 주세요
Please release my brother from the road of evil deeds.
오빠를 악의 길에서 해방시켜 주세요
Are you okay with that?
괜찮겠어요?
Do you really want that?
정말 괜찮겠어요?
But Ms. Anna isn't alone!
하지만 선생님은 혼자가 아니예요
We are with you!
우리가 곁에 있어요
I'll be with you!
제가 곁에 있어드릴 테니까요!
Thank you, En.
고마워요, 엔
Die!
죽어라!
Demos! You are unforgivable!
데모스! 난 널 용서치 않겠다!
Your torment of Ms. Anna will be paid back!
안나 선생님을 괴롭게 하는 널 말이다!
Hmph. What about that?
흥, 그게 뭐 어떻다는 거냐?!
N- no..
이, 이럴수가...
Feeling pain? I could have played with you bit more, but I must destory this planet.
괴롭나? 좀 더 놀아주고 싶지만 난 이 별을 파괴해야 돼
Dagwon, you may rest in peace for eternity too.
다그온, 너도 영원히 잠들거라
With Anna!
안나와 함께 말이다!
Farewell, Dagwon!
안녕이다, 다그온!
En!
엔!
Die!
뒈져라!
Brother...
오빠...
I also feel your pain, dear brother...
오빠의... 고통... 저도 느끼고 있어요...
Damn you!
이, 이자식...
Let's go, Demos!
간다, 데모스!
Fire Lio Sword!
파이어 라이오 소드!
This is the fate of us brother and sister.
이게... 우리 남매의... 운명이예요...
Brother...
오빠...
She isn't here!
없어!
Where did she go?
어디에 간 거지?!
Ms. Anna!
안나 선생님!
I-it can't be...
이, 이럴수가...
Ms. Anna!
안나 선생님!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
I heard that Mekaju Seijin that appeared this time is a big plant?
이번에 나타난 메카쥬 성인은 거대한 식물이라며?
Right, it's a mecha plant. It's very big!
그래, 기계 식물이야. 엄청나게 크다니까
But it's a plant anyway! Nothing to worry about.
하지만 결국은 식물이잖아? 전혀 두려울 거 없다구
This guy has a fearsome weapon!
이녀석이 가지고 있는 무기가 터무니없이 굉장해!
-Its first form is an airplane.
-And?
-먼저, 제 1단계는 비행기 형태야
-그리고?
-It transforms to a robot as its second form.
-That's nothing. We'll take it down in no time.
-제 2단계는 로봇으로 변형하지
-별거 아니라구. 그런 녀석 쯤
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! A Big Tree from Space
다음회 용자지령 다그온
우주의 거대 나무
Don't let your guard down! Its third form is what we should worry about!
방심하지 말라구! 무서운 건 제 3단계 변형이니까 말야!
A Big Tree from Space
우주의 거대 나무